

# Ricardo Dereste

# Web Developer

### **About Me**

I'm Ricardo, a 24 year old web developer dedicated to creating engaging websites. Skilled in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Sass, and React. Committed to continuous learning and delivering exceptional web experiences. Eager to contribute and collaborate.

## **Education Background**

#### **Information Technology**

 Programming, operating systems, computer networks, databases, troubleshooting, implementing efficient solutions

#### **HTML & CSS**

#### Courses

- HTML & CSS: Development Environments, File Structure and Tags
- HTML & CSS: Classes, Positioning and Flexbox
- HTML & CSS: Header, Footer and CSS Variables
- HTML & CSS: Working with Responsiveness and Project Publishing
- HTML & CSS: Practicing HTML/CSS
- HTML & CSS: Mobile-First Responsiveness
- HTML & CSS: Flexbox and Responsive Layouts
- HTML & CSS: Building Layouts with Grid

#### **JavaScript**

#### Courses

- JavaScript for Web: Create Dynamic Pages
- JavaScript: Manipulating the DOM
- JavaScript on the Web: Storing Data in the Browser
- JavaScript: Validations and Speech Recognition
- JavaScript: Consuming and Handling Data from an API
- JavaScript: Array Methods
- JavaScript: Creating Requests
- JavaScript: Validating Forms
- JavaScript from Basic to Advanced (with Node.is and Projects)
- JavaScript: Learn HTML, CSS and JavaScript

#### Sass

#### Courses

- SASS: Syntactically Spectacular CSS
- SASS and SCSS from Basic to Advanced

#### React

#### Courses

- React: Developing with JavaScript
- React: How Components Work
- React with JavaScript: Dealing with Static Files
- React: Developing in React Router with JavaScript
- React: Global State Management with ContextAPI
- React: Practicing React with Js
- React: Migrating to TypeScript
- React from Zero to Mastery (with Hooks, Router, API, Projects)

# **My Contact**

- **(** +353 086 455 6447
- Newbridge, Ireland
- ricardodeveloper.com
- github.com/RicardoDereste
- linkedin.com/in/ricardodereste

# Languages

- Portuguese Native
- English C1
- Italian B1
- Japanse Al

# **Professional Experience**

#### • Whirlpool S.A.

Location: Rio Claro, Brazil Function: Stamping Press Operator Period: Jul 2018 to May 2020

#### Web Store

Location: Rio Claro, Brazil Function: Owner and Operator Period: Jan 2020 to Nov 2022

#### Coolrain Sawmills

Location: Coolrain, Ireland Function: General Operator Period: Feb 2022 to Sep 2022

#### SuperValu

Location: Newbridge, Ireland Function: Shop Floor Assistant Period: Feb 2023 to Now